https://www.checkworks.com/more-information/privacy-policy/

Last Updated: June 26, 2020
Welcome. The aim of this Privacy Policy is to provide an overview of the privacy practices exercised by Check Works, Inc. (“Check Works,” “we,” “us,” or “our”), with respect to our website.
We want you to understand how we collect, use, and share your information. By using our website, you hereby agree to the terms set out in this Privacy Policy.
What information does Check Works collect and how is it used?
Information You Provide
You are required to provide us with information such as your name, email address, and phone number when you choose to contact us through our website. We require this information in order to respond to your inquiries and to keep track of the individuals and organizations interested in our products and services. We also collect information to fulfill online orders and manage our online client portals.
Individuals seeking employment with Check Works must provide us with personal information so that we can evaluate their qualifications and perform any necessary background checks.
Automatically Collected Information
We gather certain information automatically from our website visitors such as their IP address and unique device identifier. We use the collected information for the administration and operation of our website, to understand how visitors interact with our services, to improve our website and services, and for analytics and marketing purposes.
We also use cookies and similar tracking technologies (small bits of code stored on a visitor’s computer hard drive or device), which enable a website to “personalize” itself for each visitor by remembering information about individual visits to the website. We use cookies to store your preferences, display content based upon what you view on our website to personalize your visit, analyze trends, administer the website, track movements around the website. We may share website usage information about visitors to our website with third-party advertising companies for the purpose of managing and targeting advertisements and for market research analysis on our website.
We use Google Analytics to obtain aggregated information about the traffic and usage of our website. Google Analytics uses cookies to capture information such as the URL of the page you are viewing, your browser information, and your geographic region. We encourage you to review Google Analytics’ privacy policy to understand its privacy practices.
Our website does not respond to browser “Do Not Track” signals. However, if you wish to block cookies, you can configure your browser settings to reject them. You can also delete all cookies that are already on your computer’s hard drive by searching for and deleting files with “cookie” in them. Note that disabling some or all cookies may impair our website’s functionality.
Is my information shared?
We will share data with third parties only in the ways that are described above and:
as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process;
when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;
with trusted service providers, if required for purposes of responding to specific inquiries; or
if Check Works is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale; in such a case, you will be notified via a notification sent through email, and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your information, as well as any choices you may have.
What if I use a link on Check Works' website to visit other websites or applications?
Our website contains links to other websites and applications such LinkedIn and Twitter. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites or applications. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of each and every website or mobile application that collects personal information.
How long is my information stored?
We store your information for as long as needed: (i) to conduct business with you; (ii) as needed for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy or at the time of collection; or (iii) as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce any agreements.
Can children submit information through Check Works' website?
Our website is not intended for children under the age of 13. If you believe that we have inadvertently collected information from a child under 13, please contact us so we can promptly delete their information.
How is information protected?
We provide commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect information we obtain through our website. Please be aware that no security system is foolproof. As a result, we cannot guarantee the security of any information transmitted to us and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction, misuse, unauthorized access, alteration, or inadvertent disclosure of your information.
What if I’m a California resident?
The below chart reflects the categories of personal information we have collected from California residents both online and offline during the past twelve months, the categories of sources from which the information was collected, the business or commercial purpose for which the information was collected, and the categories of third parties with whom we shared that information.
Categories of Personal Information Collected
Categories of Sources of Collection
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
A) Identifiers such as real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, internet protocol address, email address, account name, social security number, driver's license number, passport number, or other similar identifiers.
You;Third party sources;Our website;Publicly available information.
Provide products and services to you; Respond to questions; Provide you with information about our services; Enhance customer experience; Detect security incidents and protect against fraud or illegal activity; Conduct hiring and/or other human resources activities; For research, analysis, and product development; To evaluate or process a commercial transaction;As required by applicable law or government regulation.
Affiliates; Service providers; Business partners.
B) Personal information categories listed in Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80 such as  name, signature, social security number, physical characteristics or description, address, telephone number, passport number, driver's license or state identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or any other financial information, medical information, or health insurance information.
You;Third party sources;Our website;Publicly available information.
Provide products and services to you; Respond to questions; Provide you with information about our services; Enhance customer experience; Detect security incidents and protect against fraud or illegal activity; Conduct hiring and/or other human resources activities; To evaluate or process a commercial transaction;As required by applicable law or government regulation.
Affiliates; Service providers; Business partners.
C) Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law such as age, race, national origin, citizenship, marital status, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, medical conditions (including pregnancy or childbirth, physical or mental disability or related medical conditions), parental status, veteran or military status.
You;Third party sources;Our website;Publicly available information.
Conduct hiring and/or other human resources activities.
Affiliates; Service providers.
D) Commercial information such as records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies.
We do not collect.
N/A
N/A
E) Biometric information
We do not collect.
N/A
N/A
F) Internet or other similar network activity such as browsing history, search history, information on interactions with an internet website, application, or advertisement.
You;Third party sources;Our website.
Provide services to you; Enhance customer experience;Detect security incidents and protect against fraud or illegal activity.
Service providers.
G) Geolocation data such as physical location or movements
We do not collect.
N/A
N/A
H) Sensory data such as audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information.
We do not collect.
N/A
N/A
I) Professional or employment-related information such as current and prior employment, performance evaluations, and results of background checks
You;Third party sources;Publicly available information.
Conduct hiring and/or other human resources activities.
Affiliates; Service providers.
J) Non-public education information as defined in 20 U.S.C. Section 1232g, 34 C.F.R. Part 99 such as education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial information, or student disciplinary records.
We do not collect.
N/A
N/A
K) Inferences drawn from other Personal Information to create a profile reflecting your preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitude, intelligence, ability, aptitude, and any other inferences drawn from your personal information.
We do not collect.
N/A
N/A
In the past twelve months we have disclosed personal information to third parties for business or commercial purposes. The categories of personal information we have disclosed to third parties for business or commercial purposes include categories: A, B, C, F, and I.
In the past twelve months, we have not sold personal information, and have no actual knowledge of selling the personal information of minors under 16 years of age. California residents have the right to opt out of the sale of their personal information, but because we do not sell personal information, we do not offer an opt out.
Right to Know
California residents have the right to request that we disclose the categories and specific pieces of personal information we collected, used, and disclosed during the past twelve months, the categories of sources from which their personal information was collected, our business or commercial purposes for collecting their personal information, and the categories of third parties with whom we shared their personal information.
Right to Delete
California residents have the right to request deletion of the personal information we have collected from them.
Request Submission
You or your authorized agent can submit a request here or by calling 1-866-870-5918. You will need to provide us with personal information for us to match with information we have on file in order to verify your identity and residency. The personal information that we use to verify your identity and residency will not be used for any other purpose. California residents have the right to not be discriminated against for exercising their CCPA privacy rights. We do not discriminate against California residents who exercise their CCPA privacy rights.
What happens when Check Works' Privacy Policy changes?
We will update this Privacy Policy to reflect any changes in our privacy practices. We will notify you of any non-material changes to our Privacy Policy by posting it on our website and indicating at the top the date it was last updated. Where changes are material, we will notify you in accordance with applicable law.
What if I have other questions?
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or about our privacy practices, please contact us through our website contact form or one of the other means provided on our Contact Us page.
